A Finding Aid to the Roko Gallery Records, 1929-1982, bulk 1970-1978, in the Archives of American Art AAA.rokogall
Archives of American Art
Roko Gallery records
bulk 1970-1978
1929-1982
AAA.rokogall
Archives of American Art
6 Linear feet
The Roko Gallery records measure six linear feet and date from 1929-1982, with the bulk of the records dating from 1970-1978. Founded by Michael Leon Freilich in 1946, the records of this New York contemporary art gallery consist primarily of artists files. Also found are scattered correspondence, business and financial records, a subject file, exhibition files, seven scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs of Frielich, friends, and of artwork.
Roko Gallery
Provenance
The Roko Gallery records were donated to the Archives of American Art in 1975-1988 by Ann Freilich, sister of Michael Freilich, and Cynthia Bernardi, former director of the gallery.
Restrictions on Access
Use of originals requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Michael Leon Freilich (1912-1975) established the Roko Gallery in 1946 at 51 Greenwich Avenue where it remained until the mid-1950s. Over its 32 year history, the gallery featured the paintings and sculptures of young, new artists, most living in New York City, through solo exhibitions, group shows, and sales. The gallery then made a series of moves, first to 925 Madison Avenue, then to 867 Madison Avenue, and finally back to Greenwich Village at 90 East 10st Street in 1970. In 1974, Michael Freilich became ill and the daily gallery operations were taken over by artist Lloyd Lózes Goff. Freilich passed away in February 1975; Cynthia Bernardi and Manu Sassoonian bought the gallery and became co-directors in the spring of 1975. The gallery closed in 1978, leaving open an annex on 816 Broadway.
Scope and Content Note
The Roko Gallery records measure six linear feet and date from 1929-1982, with the bulk of the records from 1970-1978. Founded by Michael Leon Freilich in 1946, the records of this New York gallery consist primarily of artists' files. Also found are scattered correspondence, business and financial records, a subject file, exhibition files, disassembled scrapbooks, printed material, and photographs.
The bulk of the correspondence is from the early to mid-1970s and concerns general gallery operations, sales of artwork, artists interested in exhibiting at the gallery, letters to Ann Freilich Schutz regarding Michael Freilich's death, and a handful of personal postcards from Freilich to his niece, 1952-1955. Scattered correspondence from artists Lambro Ahlas, Mike Cook, Hermann Dahl, Salvatore Del Deo, Raymond Dowden, Charles Kaiman, Peggy Muray (Mrs. Nicholas Muray), Raphael Soyer, George Sugarman, Anne Parker, Jan Wunderman, and Hank Virgona is also found. General business and financial records include calendars, address books, mailing lists, visitors' registers, receipt books, consignment agreements, invoices and receipts.
Measuring 3.5 linear feet, Artists Files comprise the bulk of the collection and contain correspondence, exhibition catalogs, clippings, original artwork, receipts, price lists, photographs, and slides of work. Among the nearly 200 artists are Murat Brierre, Faith Bromberg, Clare Burch, Lawrence Calcagno, Victor Candell, Arthur Cohen, Giuseppe Di Lieto, Edward Eichel, Ann Freilich, Dennis Fritz, Mary Heisig, Herbert Kallem, Doris Klein, Elizabeth Korn, Randall Morgan, Anne Parker, Dorothy Robbins, May Stevens, Hank Virgona, Walter Williams, and Jan Wunderman.
There is one subject file containing a proposal by the Rainbow Art Foundation. Exhibitions and Event files date from 1956-1978 and contain printed material, press releases, notes, correspondence, agreements, and a disassembled notebook containing prices and lists of works exhibited at the Roko Gallery from 1967-1978. Also found is typed and signed poetry by poet John Tagliabue. Disassembled scrapbooks contain additional printed materials regarding the gallery's solo and group exhibitions from 1947-1966. Among the many artists represented in the scrapbooks are Claude Clark, Beauford Delaney, Paul England, Peter Heinemann, Herbert Kallem, Herschel Levit, Si Lewen, Howard Mandel, Rose Piper, Sadie Rosenblum, Herbert Scheffel, Erika Weihs, Walter Williams, and Jan Wunderman.
Additional printed material includes mostly newspaper clippings, exhibition announcements, and catalogs. Material found in the collection that pre-dates the founding of the gallery consists primarily of printed material collected by Freilich.
Photographs, slides, and negatives date mostly from the 1970s and depict gallery directors Michael Leon Freilich, Cynthia Bernadini and Manu Sassoonian, and artwork.
Arrangement
The Roko Gallery records are arranged into eight series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1936, 1952-circa late 1970s (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
Series 2: Business and Financial Records, circa 1956-1980 (Box 1; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 3: Artist Files, circa 1948-1979 (Box 2-5; 3.5 linear feet)
Series 4: Subject Files, undated (Box 5; 1 folder)
Series 5: Exhibition and Event Files, circa 1956-1978 (Box 5; 0.3 linear feet)
Series 6: Scrapbook, circa 1947-1966 (Box 5-6; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1929-1982 (Box 6; 0.4 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographic Material, 1946-circa 1970s (Box 6; 0.3 linear feet)
Ahlas, Lambro; Bernardi, Cynthia; Brierre, Murat, 1938-; Bromberg, Faith, 1919-; Burch, Claire; Calcagno, Lawrence, 1913-; Candell, Victor, 1903-1977; Clark, Claude, 1915-; Cohen, Arthur Allen, 1928-; Cook, Mike; Dahl, Hermann; Del Deo, Salvatore, 1928-; Di Lieto, Giuseppe; Dowden, Raymond Baxter, 1905-1982; Eichel, Edward V., 1932-; England, Paul; Freilich, Ann; Freilich, Michael Leon, 1912-1975; Fritz, Dennis, 1937-; Heinemann, Peter, 1931-; Heisig, Mary, 1913-; Kaiman, Charles, 1947-; Kallem, Herbert, 1909-1994; Klein, Doris, 1918-; Korn, Elizabeth P.; Levit, Herschel; Lewen, Si; Mandel, Howard, 1917-1999; Morgan, Randall, 1920-; Muray, Peggy; Parker, Anne Eaton, 1919-; Piper, Rose; Rainbow Art Foundation; Robbins, Dorothy; Rosenblum, Sadie; Sassoonian, Manu; Scheffel, Herbert; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987; Stevens, May; Sugarman, George, 1912-1999; Tagliabue, John, 1923-; Virgona, Hank; Weihs, Erika; Williams, Walter, 1920-; Wunderman, Jan Darcourt, 1921-; Wunderman, Jan, 1921; Address books; Art galleries, Commercial--New York (State)--New York; Art, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Artists--New York (State); Calendars; Exhibition catalogs; Financial records; Gallery directors; Gallery records; Photographs; Poems; Scrapbooks; Visitors books; Works of art
- Correspondence, 1936, 1952-circa late 1970s; Series 1; (Box 1; 0.2 linear feet)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence is with gallery directors Michael Freilich and Cynthia Bernadini, and to a lesser degree, Manu Sassoonian and Lloyd Lózes Goff. Topics cover general gallery operations, sales of artwork, artists interested in exhibiting at the gallery, and letters to Ann Freilich Schutz regarding Michael Freilich's death. In addition, there is a small group of personal postcards from Freilich to his niece, 1952-1955. Scattered correspondence with artists includes Lambro Ahlas, Mike Cook, Hermann Dahl, Salvatore Del Deo, Raymond Dowden, Charles Kaiman, Peggy Muray (Mrs. Nicholas Muray), Raphael Soyer, George Sugarman, Anne Parker Wigglesworth, Jan Wunderman, and Hank Virgona. Additional correspondence with artists is also found in Artist Files, circa 1946-1979.
  Arrangement note
  Folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1936, 1952-circa late 1970s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1975 January - June (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1975 July (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1975 August - December (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Business and Financial Records, circa 1956-1980; Series 2; (Box 1; 0.8 linear feet)
  Business and financial records include calendars, address books, mailing lists, visitors' registers, receipt books, consignment agreements mostly from 1975-1977, invoices and receipts, and materials for tax returns. The bulk of the records are from the mid-1970s.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Address Book and Loose Names/Addresses, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Calendar, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Calendars, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Calendars, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Consignment Agreements, Artists A-G, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Consignment Agreements, Artists H-Q, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Consignment Agreements, Artists R-Z, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Consignment Agreements, Miscellaneous, 1963, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Engagement Books, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Invoices/Receipts, 1970-1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Legal Forms, 1975-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Mailing Labels, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mailing Lists, 1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Notes, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Notes, 1970-1978, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Press Notices, Mailing Lists, circa 1956-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Receipt Books, 1964-1965, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Receipt Books, 1975 February - 1978 June (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Receipt Books, 1977 October - 1978 February (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Tax Materials, 1959, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Visitors Register, 1970 January 31 - 1972 October 31 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Visitors Register, 1972 November - 1975 June (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Visitors Register, 1975 June 21 - 1978 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Artist Files, circa 1948-1979; Series 3; (Box 2-5; 3.5 linear feet)
  Artist files contain correspondence, exhibition catalogs, clippings, original artwork, receipts and lists, photographs, and slides of work. Among the nearly 200 artists are Murat Brierre, Faith Bromberg, Claire Burch, Lawrence Calcagno, Victor Candell, Arthur Cohen, Giuseppe Di Lieto, Edward Eichel, Ann Freilich, Dennis Fritz, Mary Heisig, Herbert Kallem, Doris Klein, Elizabeth Korn, Stefan Martin, Randall Morgan, Anne Parker, Dorothy Robbins, May Stevens, Hank Virgona, Walter Williams, and Jan Wunderman.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by the artist's last name.
  - Rosters of Artists, 1972, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Abrams, Ruth, 1959, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Ahlas, Lambro, 1972-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Aiken, Mary Hoover, 1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Allen, Abe, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Amantea, Christopher, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Atkins, Jerry, 1977-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Bageris, John, 1956, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Baranik, Rudolf, 1958-1964, 1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bayor, Andrew, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bek-Gran, Robert, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Ben-Zion, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Bennett, Gale, 1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Black, Harold, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Block, Dorothy, 1955, 1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Brierre, Murat, 1967-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
  - Brigadier, Anne, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Brodsky, Stan, 1973-1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bromberg, Faith, 1974-1977, undated (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - Brown, Carol, 1970-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Burch, Claire, 1962-1971, undated (Box 2, Folder 25-28)
  - Burr, Steven, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Calcagno, Lawrence, 1962-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 30-32)
  - Cameron, Polly, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Candell, Victor, 1972-1978, undated (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Case, Malcom Edgar, 1951, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Case, Reginald, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Cassanelli, Victor, 1971, 1975, undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Chapman, Robert, 1963-1966, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Christopher, William, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Cohen, Adele, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Cohen, Arthur, 1970-1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 42-43)
  - Comins, Jeremy, 1962, 1965, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Craig, Martin, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Crampton, Nancy, 1976, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Currie, Bruce, 1960-1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Davis, Esther, 1967, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Delaney, Beauford, 1961, 1964-1978 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - DeMauro, Don, 1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Detweiler, Russell, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Di Lieto, Giuseppe (Peppino), 1962, 1967-1969, undated (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
  - Dimondstein, Morton, 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Diska, Pat, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Dobbs, John, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Dorcely, Roland, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - DuBack, Charles, 1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Efrem, Myrl, 1955, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Egris, Ruth, Ted and Charles, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Eichel, Edward, 1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 61-62)
  - Elmaleh, Victor, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ely, Richard, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Esman, Betty, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ettinger, Stephen, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Evans, Minnie, 1975-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Farrugio, Remo, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Feder, Jack, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fejes, Claire, 1961-1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Finkelstein, Louis, 1956, 1960, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Flack, Audrey, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Flynn, Charles, 1972, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Frank, Trudi, 1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Frei, Linae, 1976-1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Freilich, Ann, 1949-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 14-17)
  - Freund, Marjorie, 1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Fritz, Dennis, 1967-1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
  - Gambini, William, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Garner, Joan, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Giorgi, Fiorenzo, 1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Giron, Xavier, 1970-1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Goff, Lloyd Lózes, 1960-1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Golbin, Andrée, 1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Gold, Fay, 1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Gourevitch, Jacqueline, 1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Goyri, Roberto González, 1952, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Gregory, Bruce, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Gromberg, Jacob, 1962, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Heinemann, Peter, 1954-1956, 1959, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Heisig, Mary, 1949-1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 33-35)
  - Helsy, Kate, 1963, 1968, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Hirschberg, Phyllis, 1966, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Homitzky, Peter, 1974, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Huff, Linda, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Interian, Luis, undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Jackson, Clifford, 1958, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Jagel, John, 1962, 1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Jones, Amy, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Kaiman, Charles, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Kainen, Jacob, 1961-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Kallem, Herbert, 1948-1977, undated (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
  - Katz, Alex, 1957, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Klein, Doris, 1967-1972, undated (Box 3, Folder 49-51)
  - Klein, Ruth, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Klement, Vera, 1950, 1958, 1960, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 53-54)
  - Koppelman, Chaim, 1973, undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Korn, Elizabeth, 1967-1975, undated (Box 3, Folder 56-60)
  - Kotuk-Krauss, Maggie, 1975-1978, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Kovacevic, Boža, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kuh, Howard, 1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Ladenson, Sam, 1971-1973 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Laks, Sylvia, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Langlais, Bernard, 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Lasky, Stephen J., undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - La Verdiere, Bruno, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Leaf, Ruth, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Leiber, Gerson A., 1963-1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Levine, Marion Lerner, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Levit, Herschel, 1958, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Lewen, Si, 1948-1959, 1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Licht, Evelyn, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Li-Fa, Shaih, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Long, Hubert, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Lubalin, Sylvia, 1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Lubner, Lorraine, 1969-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Lubner, Martin, 1975-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Mandel, Howard, 1956-1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Martin, Stefan, 1961-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Martin, Stefan, 1970, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Martin, Stefan, undated (Box 4, Folder 22-23)
  - McCartin, Jan, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Melnicoff, Mitzi, 1964-1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Metz, Frank, 1961-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Miller, Shirley U., 1969-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Mitchell, Fred, 1970, 1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Morgan, Maud, 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Morgan, Randall, 1957-1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 31-32)
  - Moscan, Hannah, 1957, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Moss, Milton, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Muller, Marion, 1972-1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Myerson, Margery Deckinger, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Nagase, Yoshiro, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Nappi, Nicholas, 1963-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Neel, Alice, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Nelson, Don, 1975-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Nelson, Robert A., 1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Nodjoumi, Nickzad, 1977-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Orkin, Ruth, 1974-1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Ossaye, Roberto, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Parker, Anne, 1968-1978, undated (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
  - Parker, Robert Andrew, 1950-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 47-48)
  - Perigord, J., undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Perret, Nell, 1976, undated (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Phillips, Blanche, 1957, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Pierucci, Massimo, 1970, 1973, undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Piper, Rose, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Polakov, Lester, 1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 54-55)
  - Powell, Leslie, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Powers, Elizabeth, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Regensburg, Sophy, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Reid, Charles, 1972-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Revi, Leo, 1973-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Richards, Ken, 1971, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Robbins, Dorothy, 1964, 1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 62-64)
  - Roeburt, undated (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Rohowsky, Meyers, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Rosenblum, Sadie, 1959-1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 67-68)
  - Rosenquit, Bernard, 1955-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Rutledge, James, 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Schnurr-Colflesh, E., 1977 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Schreyer, Greta, 1978-1979, undated (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Schuller, Grete, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Seidler, Doris, 1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Selden, Ellen, 1967-1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 75-76)
  - Seley, Clara, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Seley, Jason, undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Shahn, Ben, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Shiffrin, Roy, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Simon, Sidney, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Smith, Robert L., 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Sonenberg, Jack, 1962, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Soshana, 1957-1965 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Spitz, Sherie, 1967-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Stavropoulos, Theo, 1965-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Steig, Arthur, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stevens, May, 1962-1970, undated (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - Storm, Nikolaj, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Suhl, Yuri, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sweat, Lynn, 1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Tabachnick, Anne, 1971-1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Tarlow, Lois, 1975-1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Tasch, Frederick, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Thompson, Brian M., undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Tytell, Louis, 1962-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Velay, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Vennekamp, Johannes, 1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Vevers, Tony, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Virgona, Hank, circa 1970-1978 (Box 5, Folder 17-19)
  - Waldenfels, C.V., undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Wasserman, Helene, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Weihs, Erika, 1961-1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
  - Weymouth, Fleur, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Williams, Walter, 1957-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 25-27)
  - Wunderman, Jan, 1963-1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 28-29)
- Subject Files, undated; Series 4; (Box 5; 1 folder)
  Subject files contains one folder of a proposal by the Rainbow Art Foundation.
  - Rainbow Art Foundation, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Exhibition and Event Files, circa 1956-1978; Series 5; (Box 5; 0.3 linear feet)
  Anniversary and group exhibitions, a memorial exhibition to Michael Freilich, and events held at the Roko Gallery are documented through printed material, press releases, notes, price lists of works, correspondence, and agreements. Material regarding solo and group exhibitions from 1967-1978 is found in a disassembled notebook containing prices and lists of works exhibited at the Roko Gallery between 1967-1978. Also found in the event files is typed and signed poetry by poet John Tagliabue. Additional material regarding exhibitions from 1947-1966 may be found in Scrapbooks, circa 1947-1966.
  Exhibitions are filed before events. Among the exhibition files, exhibition schedules and a disassembled notebook are filed first, followed by exhibition folders arranged chronologically. Event files are arranged chronologically.
  - Exhibitions
    - Exhibition Schedules, 1962-1965, 1975-1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Notebook of Exhibition Lists/Prices, Artists A-G, 1967-1977 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Notebook of Exhibition Lists/Prices, Artists H-Z, 1967-1977 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Notebook of Exhibition Lists/Prices, Group Shows, 1971-1978 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - 10th Anniversary Exhibition (November 17 - December 7, 1956) (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Artists Critics (October 3-26, 1962) (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Group Exhibition (January 1966) (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - 20th Anniversary Exhibition (December 10, 1966 - January 4, 1967) (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Group Exhibition (June 1-23, 1967), circa 1967 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - American Graphic Art Exhibition (May 11-31, 1968) (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Group Exhibition (June 4-28, 1968) (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Group Exhibition (June 3-24, 1970), 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - 24th Anniversary Exhibition (1970), circa 1970 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Group Exhibition (June 2-30, 1971), circa 1971 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - 25th Anniversary Exhibition - Homage to the Tanager (December 4-31, 1971), circa 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Group Exhibition (June 2-23, 1972), circa 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Group Exhibition (June 5-29, 1973), circa 1968-1973 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Group Exhibition, circa 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - "Line, Form, Vision" (Sept. 27-Oct. 18, 1975) (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Memorial to Michael (February 3-28, 1976), circa 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Miniatures Exhibition (November 22-January 4, 1976), circa 1975 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Ten American Collagists Exhibition (February 1-27, 1977), circa 1977 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - 31st Annual Group Exhibition (April 1-27, 1977), circa 1977 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Group Exhibition (June 1-30, 1977), circa 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - The Tenth Street Exhibition (December 10, 1977 - January 8, 1978), circa 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Group Drawing Exhibition, "Retreat from Reality" (January 1-28, 1978), circa 1978 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - 32nd Annual Group Exhibition (April 1-29, 1978), circa 1978 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Roko Gallery, Miscellaneous, 1956, 1975, undated (Box 5, Folder 58)